Front-end web engineer.

Email <u>sidney@sidney.me</u>
GitHub notsidney

GitHub <u>notsidney</u> Website <u>sidney.me</u>

**About** 

Front-end web engineer passionate about the intersection of technology and design. Interested in building consumer software and user experiences that make life easier. Self-taught web development and UI/UX design. Coding on the web since 2010.

Experience

## Antler

Sydney

Global early-stage VC. Runs local startup generator programs for talented people.

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### JAN 2020 - AUG 2021

- Developed the <u>virtual Demo Day platform</u>, allowing Antler locations to present these events online during Covid-19. Hosted 12 events with 10,000+ viewers in its first year.
- Co-developed Fusion tech platform used by thousands of founders during expansion to 5 new locations. Rapidly iterated on user-facing apps, releasing features monthly.
- Built internal tools to speed up development, later open-sourced as <u>npm packages</u>.
- Wrote <u>blog posts</u> promoting Antler products featured on major online publications.

2hats Sydney

Former startup. Connected talented uni students to startups to make a swift impact.

#### **FULL STACK ENGINEER**

JUL 2019 - NOV 2019

- Led development on a complete redesign of the student-facing web portal to improve user experience and retention. Improved rate of userbase growth by 150%.
- Refactored code to TypeScript and improved documentation to optimise development.
- Maintained and extended back-end serverless architecture for new business goals.
- Interviewed and assessed candidates. Presented company tech talk at a university.

### JUNIOR FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

AUG 2018 - JUL 2019

- Co-developed new React web portal a month before launch. Grew userbase by 40%.
- Assisted in code refactoring to React Hooks from Redux just as it was first released. Reduced amount of code written by 30% and halved JS payload size.
- Learnt and built on top of a serverless architecture with Google Cloud Firestore, Cloud Functions and CI/CD with Bitbucket Pipelines on the job without prior experience.
- Promoted the company at university events, actively driving sign ups and engagement.

Skills

- **Front-end web development.** React + Hooks, responsive CSS + SCSS, ES6+, TypeScript. npm modules, semantic HTML, browser compatibility, web performance.
- Implementing UI/UX designs. Strong attention to detail and typography. Pixel-perfect recreations of designs. Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, XD, Sketch.
- Team-based development and collaboration. Git. Strong communication skills.
- Back-end web development. Google Cloud Firestore + Functions, Node.js. CI/CD with Bitbucket Pipelines, Netlify. Also familiar with Python, Bash shell.

#### Education

# Bachelor of Advanced Computing

# THE UNIVERSITY OF SYDNEY

2018 - 19

Received Sydney Scholars Award and accepted into Dalyell Scholars program.